Jake Zimmermann

T: 07545128394

E: jake zimmermann@hotmail.co.uk

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-zimmermann-66776339/

Github CV: https://github.com/JakeOtto



Personal Profile

Junior Data Engineer with hands-on experience as a WordPress developer for various clients. My ability to solve complex problems, observe and analyse data effectively, and rapidly acquire new technical skills have been instrumental in executing personal and team projects, fuelling my passion for a career in Data Engineering. Previous experience in management roles has cultivated strong teamwork and communication abilities, essential for collaborative work environments and community projects. Additionally, my growing proficiency in AI interaction, coupled with over a decade of customer service experience, has equipped me with exceptional client-facing skills and a community-centric approach.

Experience

Proof Of Treasure – Private project

January 2022 - Present

- https://proofoftreasure.com
- Developing programming skills with Chialisp (token transactions).
- Building discord.py bots for community/staff interactions allowing more efficient team task management.
- Public game creation methods as well as accuracy checks.
- Working with a small developer team.

WordPress developer/teacher – Barnet Market

December 2021 - Ongoing

- https://barnet-market.co.uk
- Working with clients in person helping them develop skills for their own personal site maintenance and improvements.

WordPress developer - The After 30s Podcast

July 2020 – September 2021

- Managing, testing and optimising TA30s website using Google Analytics.
- Managing and implementing new content with WordPress CMS.
- Reporting bugs and suggesting improvements of the website to clients.
- Providing monthly website reports highlighting key metrics and on-site opportunities.
- Competitor research.
- On-site SEO.

IT support technician - London Metropolitan University

November 2017 – October 2019

- Managing accounts and providing first and second line support to the university students and faculty members.
- Working with system administration tools.
- Personal and group face to face support meetings.
- Working as part of a larger team.

Development Tools & Languages

Development tools

Visual Studio, Bluestacks, Eclipse, Glassfish, NetBeans, Slack, GitHub, Android Studio, GCP, React, Pytest, AWS, Docker, Flask, RDBs, S3, EC2, AWS Lambda, Kafka, Kaggle

Languages used

Java, JavaScript, Python, CSS, PHP, Chialisp, SQL

Education

Makers Academy - Data engineering specialization

Sept 04 - January 14th, 2024

TDD and Object-Oriented-Programming focused in Python (agile, waterfall and free flowing development)

SQL and data processing

Data analysis and presenting insights

Data warehouse modelling

Git source control

AWS Services, RDBs, EC2s, Lambda, S3 Buckets

Apache Airflow and DAG design

Charity/ Personal Experiences

- Teaching Math and PE Namanga Christian School, Kenya.
- Teaching, site construction Brothers of the Sacred Heart Zambia.
- Volunteer chef Paradise Parks kids' community centre.
- Development of personal languages, German, Mandarin.
- Mathematics revision centre popup mathematics revision centre, leaning business opening legalities and teaching skills.
- Coaching 2 years coaching in a popular e-sport, developing my confidence in making a
 viable career from a personal hobby. Further improving my communication skills through
 explaining concepts clearly and well to customers.
- London Youth Olympics three years Volleyball representative for Barnet, developing teamwork skills. Previously playing rugby for Saracen's youth teams too.
- Management roles
 - Restaurant manager Bufle, Rupert Street W1
 - Payrole, delegation, licencing, site management requirements, HR roles Duty manager Q.E. Girls sport centre
 - Delegation, rota/schedule management, staff teaching